Guide to the Cornelius W. de Kiewiet papers, 1923-1950
de Kiewiet, Cornelius W. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornelius W. de Kiewiet papers, 1923-1950
3-7-372
De Kiewiet, C. W.(Cornelius William),
1.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, manuscripts, research materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal papers of de Kiewiet consisting of correspondence to and from de Kiewiet in South Africa, Rhodesia, London, Paris, Berlin, Iowa City, and Ithaca; also, lecture notes, records of Cornell University's Army Intensive Language Program, a diploma, photographs, and miscellaneous reflective and creative writings.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor, dean, provost, and acting president of Cornell University, 1941-51; subsequently president of the University of Rochester.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal papers of de Kiewiet consisting of correspondence to and from de Kiewiet in South Africa, Rhodesia, London, Paris, Berlin, Iowa City, and Ithaca; also, lecture notes, records of Cornell University's Army Intensive Language Program, a diploma, photographs, and miscellaneous reflective and creative writings.
Letter from C. W. de Kiewiet to Deane W. Malott, December 30, 1960, replying to a letter of sympathy on the death of de Kiewiet's daughter. de Kiewiet recalls Paul Tillich, while talking about the international conflict, saying that the great efforts that we are making to maintain ourselves are also the great efforts which may destroy us.
SUBJECTS
Names:
De Kiewiet, C. W. 1902-1986.; Malott, Deane W. (Deane Waldo), 1898-1996.; Tillich, Paul, 1886-1965.; Cornell University. Army Intensive Russian Language Program.; University of Rochester.
Subjects:
Economic history -- Medieval, 500-1500.; Creative writing.; Political science
Places:
South Africa -- History.; Rhodesia -- Politics and government.; South Africa
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Commencement Address, 1948-06-14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Inauguration - University of Rochester, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photograph, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Russian Army Program, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1939-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Russian Army Program, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Russian Army Program, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Russian Army Program, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Economic and Social History of South Africa, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Notes and Essays, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Notes and Essays, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Notes and Essays, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Notes and Essays, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Notes and Essays, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Notes, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Notes - Greek Art, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Notes, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Notes - Polland, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Notes - Classical History, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Notes - Classical and Mediaeval History, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Lecture Notes, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Notes - Middle Ages, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Notes, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Drafts - South Africa, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Paper - West African Conference, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Correspondence - Finances, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Student Term Papers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Student Papers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Student Papers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Correspondence, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1926-1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1929-10 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1929-09 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1929-12 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1933-1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1922-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1923-1929 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Photographs, Undated"> (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence and Poetry, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence and 1923 Agenda, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 17)